Hello everyone and welcome back
to English Pod, my name is Marco.
And my name is Kathryn
and today we have an
exciting lesson for everyone
out there, very cultural.
Exactly, very closely
related to our Halloween
lesson that we had,
but on this occasion
we're going to be
looking at all Saints Day.
Alright, so this is a
festival that celebrated
in many different
countries and we're learning
today about some of the
ceremonies and practices
in those countries that are very
closely tied to those local cultures.
Exactly, so we're
going to learn a little bit
about culture and at the
same time we're going
to learn some great
words and phrases, so
let's get started with this
dialogue for the first time.
"The day of the dead has arrived
all souls day and all Saints Day.
" Your neighbor is crazy,
why is he screaming that?
Because today is the first of
November, "The Day of the Dead.
" Oh, that's right.
This is a very special
day among many cultures
around the world,
especially in Latin America.
Seriously?
I thought it was just like any
other day, except for the fact
that people visit the cemetery
and remember their loved ones.
Well, that's just part of it.
People across the world
celebrate in different ways.
In Mexico, for example,
it's common to see people
building private altars
honoring the deceased,
causing sugar skulls,
preparing the favorite
foods and beverages of the departed,
and visiting graves with these as gifts.
In the Philippines, the tombs
are cleaned or repainted.
Candles are lit and flowers are offered.
Entire families camp
out in cemeteries and
sometimes spend a night or
two near the relative's tombs.
"Whoa, that's scary.
I don't know if I could do that.
" Why?
We should fear the living, not the dead.
Then we're back, so did
you know about these
traditions in the
Philippines and in Mexico?
I know about the Mexican
ones, because there's
a lot of Mexicans
where I come from in
Chicago, and they still
celebrate these things.
But I didn't know about the Philippines,
so I found this really interesting.
Interesting, right?
Actually, yeah, the
Philippines as well as
Mexico are very Catholic
countries, so maybe
that's one of the reasons
why they have such
events that are so
important for their culture.
I'm sure.
Yeah.
Before we start talking a
little bit more about the
culture, why don't we take a
look at language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
The first word is a very common word,
especially if you're a church going person.
The word is alter.
Okay, an alter.
An alter.
It's a thing.
It's a thing, and an alter is usually
found inside a church, as you said, right?
That's right.
So it's like a table.
It's like a table.
Or a counter.
So the altar in the
church is where the priest
does all of the stuff that
he does during the Mass.
It's where he prepares the bread and the
wine, and it's essentially a table, yeah.
But you can build an altar for yourself
in your garden, for example, right?
And it doesn't have to do with
the Catholic religion, necessarily.
No, not necessarily.
You could have an altar
in a Greek pagan temple
where you give offerings
to a god or goddess.
And so in this case, an altar
is a special religious table
where you perform certain
religious rites or functions.
Okay, very interesting.
All right.
And so it's common in Mexico for people to
build private altars honoring the deceased.
So what is this word?
Deceased.
All right.
Deceased is a noun.
It's a word that we used to call
someone who's dead or departed.
So the deceased was named John Smith.
So it's like a more technical
term of saying somebody is dead.
Right.
So it's something that
you'll often read in the
newspaper when they don't
want to say the dead guy.
You know, they say the deceased was a
doctor and he is survived by three children.
And so deceased is a way to
describe person in a nicer way.
Right.
Very good.
And you mentioned another word that's very
closely related to deceased, the departed.
That's right.
And this is actually a
famous word because of
a Martin Scorsese movie that
came out about two years ago.
And departed, you know
the word to depart to
leave, the person that is a
departed is someone who has left us.
It's left dead.
This world.
Yeah.
It's a dead person.
So you can say the
deceased or the departed,
which basically means the same thing
as the dead guy or the dead person.
Exactly.
But again, it's much more polite.
It's something that we hear often at
funerals or that we read in magazines.
Okay.
So for example, all Saint-State is
a way of honoring the departed.
Exactly.
Very nice sounding.
All right.
So talking a little bit more about
the departed and the traditions.
It says here that many
Mexicans use sugar skulls
or have sugar skulls
during this festivity.
That's right.
So a skull is the bones
from a person's head.
All right.
And so you can often
see these on, for example,
pirate ships, we say
skull and crossbones.
And so it's the bones from a head
and you have the bones underneath.
And it's a very popular image
on Halloween because it's scary.
Yeah.
But a skull is essentially
the bones from a head.
So it's like a person's head without
the skin, eyes, lips, everything.
Right.
It's scary because it
has empty black spaces
where the eyes are supposed to be and you
can see all the teeth, but nothing else.
What about the sugar skulls?
What are these?
They're skulls made of sugar.
That's right.
And so they look like
skulls because there's
no cheeks and no,
they're not really, there's
no skin or eyes, but
they're beautiful because
the Mexicans in their
tradition, they color the sugar.
So you can have white
skulls with this beautiful
green and pink and
red and blue decorations.
And you can eat them
because they're made of sugar.
And so it's a special
treat that people have in
the Mexican tradition
on the day of the dead.
Very good.
All right.
And one of the many
traditions apart from
sugar skulls and building
private altars, they
also visit the person's
tomb, if possible, right?
Exactly.
So a tomb is an important word.
So what is a tomb?
A tomb is a place where
someone is buried, it's
a space or a place and
it can be big or small.
But it's essentially the
resting place of a dead person.
All right.
So a tomb, where the person is and actually
on the tomb you have the tombstone, right?
That's right.
And a tombstone is the same as a gravestone
and it's a piece of rock on which you write
the name and the birth date and the death
date of the person that is buried there.
Right.
So that's the tombstone.
Very good.
Okay.
So an interesting amount of
words here on language takeaway.
Why don't we listen
to this dialogue again
and we'll be right back
with Fluency Builder.
Your neighbor is crazy.
Why is he screaming that?
Because today is the first of
November, the day of the dead.
Oh, that's right.
This is a very special
day among many cultures
around the world,
especially in Latin America.
Seriously?
I thought it was just like any
other day except for the fact
that people visit the cemetery
and remember their loved ones.
Well, that's just part of it.
People across the world
celebrate in different ways.
In Mexico, for example,
it's common to see people
building private altars
honoring the deceased,
using sugar skulls,
preparing the favorite
foods and beverages of the departed
and visiting graves with these as gifts.
In the Philippines, the tombs
are cleaned or repainted.
Candles are lit and flowers are offered.
Entire families camp
out in cemeteries and
sometimes spend a night or
two near the relative's tombs.
Whoa.
That's scary.
I don't know if I could do that.
Why?
We should fear the living.
Not the dead.
Alright, we're back,
so why don't we look at
three main phrases
on Fluency Builder now.
Fluency Builder.
Well, the first phrase should
be obvious by now because
it is the name of the
holiday we're talking about.
And the name is the Day of the Dead.
The Day of the Dead.
So this is their day.
It is.
And it's the Day of the
Dead because it's the
day in which people around
the world celebrate the departed.
It's when they talk about and remember
people that they've loved who've died.
Okay.
So it's not really like a sad day, right?
It's more of a happy remembering them and
honoring them and how much you missed them.
But in a good way.
Exactly.
And you're not actually going to hear this
very often in reference to American culture
because it's not something Americans
do and English people don't do either.
But people when
they're talking about their
own families and
traditions, we want to talk
about this because
in the Philippines or in
Latin America you have a very
strong tradition of celebrating this.
Mm-hmm.
And as we mentioned this day is
a is a day to honor or to remember
your loved ones and that's our
second phrase, your loved ones.
The phrase loved ones
might not be obvious to
many people because you can
love many people and many things.
But loved ones is a
phrase that generally
means the people that you care about
the most, your friends and your family.
So you could say, I want to have a party
but I only want my loved ones to be there.
Okay.
Or he was in the hospital and
all of his loved ones visited him.
So all those people,
not necessarily only
family, his friends and
family that you love.
Exactly.
And so those are the people in the
world that are the very closest to you.
Okay.
And our last phrase
and probably one of the
most interesting
traditions that we were able
to see in this dialogue
is that people in the
Philippines camp out in cemeteries
on their family or loved ones too.
That's right.
Camp out means to stay overnight,
to bring food and the tent or blankets.
And it essentially means to
make a camp so you can stay there.
And this is very unusual to me because
I can't imagine sleeping in a graveyard.
I think I get the goosebumps.
Right.
So camp out or you
can just say camp, right?
You don't necessarily
have to say both of them.
Right.
You can camp or you
can camp out and camp
out generally means that you're
staying in a place that is temporary.
Okay.
Very good.
So interesting phrases as
well on fluency builder today.
Let's listen to the dialogue for
the last time and we'll be right back.
The day of the dead has arrived
all souls day and all saints day.
Your neighbor is crazy.
Why is he screaming that?
Because today is the first of
November, the day of the dead.
Oh, that's right.
This is a very special
day among many cultures
around the world,
especially in Latin America.
Seriously?
I thought it was just like any
other day, except for the fact
that people visit the cemetery
and remember their loved ones.
Well, that's just part of it.
People across the world
celebrate in different ways.
In Mexico, for example,
it's common to see people
building private altars
honoring the deceased,
using sugar skulls,
preparing the favorite
foods and beverages of the departed
and visiting graves with these as gifts.
In the Philippines, the tombs
are cleaned or repainted.
Candles are lit and flowers are offered.
Entire families camp
out in cemeteries and
sometimes spend a night or
two near the relative tombs.
Whoa, that's scary.
I don't know if I could do that.
Why?
We should fear the living, not the dead.
All right, we're back.
So Catherine, you
mentioned that in Anglo-Saxon
culture, England or
in the United States.
You don't have this type of tradition of
honoring the dead or something like that.
But you do visit the tomb of your
loved ones, or the cemetery as well, right?
People do, definitely.
But you just don't have a
national day where you do this.
Well, Veterans Day is a
day when we celebrate
people who were killed in wars
or people who participated in wars.
So in America, we have
a day called Memorial
Day, which we remember the people who have
died serving the country in the military.
And so Memorial Day
is a day in which many
people like to go to the graveyards and
to lay flowers or to remember the dead.
But it really depends on your family.
I mean, some people
like to go the day a person
died and on the anniversary
or on a special day for them.
So it's very private and
personal and individual.
It's not something that we
all do on one particular day.
Right, right.
And I think what may strike many people as
a different is that you visit the cemetery.
And if you ever have
the chance to be in
Mexico or in a Hispanic country,
you will see that it's full of people.
And it's actually a, there's a lot of food
and people are there eating on the tomb.
And just, and they've actually prepared
the food that was the deceased's favorite.
Wow.
That's really nice,
though, as a gesture,
because it's another way
to remember the person
and to celebrate how things
that were happy for them exactly.
And it's a way of actually
sharing a meal with
that person, even though that person
isn't with you anymore in this world.
So yeah, it's actually very interesting.
It goes back again
to a little bit of the
culture and the folk grow and
everything from different countries.
But we want to know
what you guys do or how
you remember your
disease because each country
has its own particular little
very interesting way of doing it.
That's right.
So please share with us
on our website EnglishPod.
com, your own traditions and the culture
that you have in your home country or town.
And we're very curious
to hear those, but
also if you have
questions, as always, please
ask, because we're
happy to answer those.
All right.
So we'll see you guys there.
Bye, everyone.
Bye.